Security engineer currently working on vehicle product security. Experience in creating a secure development life-cycle at multiple companies. Actively involved in the larger security industry. Significant background in software engineering including embedded systems, web systems, and client-side software.

Primarily interested in reliability, safety, and security of software systems.

#### Experience

### **HARMAN International** / Security Engineer

JANUARY 2018 - PRESENT, NOVI, MI

- A critical player in creating and performing many aspects of the "Secure Development Lifecycle", including threat analysis and risk assessment, secure development practices, and incident response.
- Performed implementation audits on C/C++/Java codebases and reported over 20 security vulnerabilities.
- Co-created the vulnerability management process and architecture for the organization. Designed and implemented a global vulnerability management web platform to facilitate that.
- Significant work on automating secure development across the organization as much as possible (sometimes called DevSecOps).
- Designed the company's incident response process.
- Acted as lead incident responder several times and was publicly thanked by a researcher.

### **Lear Corporation** / Cybersecurity Engineering Intern

MAY 2017 - DECEMBER 2017, ANN ARBOR, MI

- Responsible for research, design, and implementation of an in-house CAN network intrusion detection system that will be provided as options to automotive OEMs.
- Created the "Threat Analysis and Risk Assessment (TARA)" process and co-authored the corresponding template used to analyze internal programs.
- Performed TARAs on various programs which found (and suggested mitigations to) many security issues.
- Technical lead for a formal analysis of static analysis tools in order to improve security quality across the global organization.
- Research and implementation of secure "Over-The-Air" update frameworks for embedded systems.

### **HARMAN International** / Software Engineering Intern (Navigation)

MAY 2016 - APRIL 2017, NOVI, MI

- Navigation product engineering for high-end, QNX-based, automotive infotainment systems.
- Designed, built, and supported an internal, automated, navigation testing infrastructure that caught several critical crashes before entering production.
- Developed a code performance analysis library for use in several projects.

### Lathrup Industries / Software & Database Developer

JANUARY 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2016, NOVI, MI

- Co-created Lathrup's internal database system (using Intuit's QuickBase service). Built API wrappers for various languages to be used in many in-house applications. System valued at \$200,000 / year.
- Found a security vulnerability in a third-party's server-side document generator application and replaced it with a client-side, in-house version. This saved the company > \$1000 / year.
- Created an automation server which performed common tasks for the company automatically. This reduced required effort and increased procedural reliability, valued at > \$55,000 / year.
- Designed and implemented the company's website.
- Built various in-house applications used with our database. This included a time clocking system

#### Education

## Georgia Institute Of Technology / MS Computer Science

JANUARY 2019 - PRESENT (Expected Graduation: 2022), Remote

• Coursework: Advanced Operating Systems

# The University of Michigan / BSE Computer Science / 3.4 GPA / Cum Laude

JANUARY 2016 - APRIL 2018, Ann Arbor, MI

• Significant technical coursework including algorithms, operating systems, computer architecture, security, compiler design and more.

used by all employees and a task management system.

### **External Work**

- Involved in the Auto-ISAC Best Practices Working Group.
  - o APRIL 2018 PRESENT
- Represent Harman on the Uptane project (a framework for secure over-the-air updates).
  - This includes involvement in the IEEE-ISTO Uptane working group.
  - o APRIL 2018 PRESENT
- Active contributor to open source projects like Mozilla Thunderbird for many years.
  - o Front-end, theme, and UX from 2012 2015
  - Security from 2018 PRESENT